Are you sure you've corrected the problem, Dr. Sinclair?
Absolutely, Mr. Luther.
Simulations of Ovin positive.
Increasing the thermal variance by 98% should eliminate the separation impurity.
Six months of this and all you had to do was turn up the heat?
Well, it's not that simple, Mr. Luther.
I mean, the composition of these meteor rocks is highly unusual.
Calculating the exact temperature was a challenge.
One I hope you're up to.
If this works, I'll leave a mark on the world no one will ever forget.
It won't hurt your bank account, either.
Initiating sequence.
Thermal sequence initiated.
Increasing thermal output.
70%.
Come on, come on.
Approaching optimum thermal reaction.
Opening the irradiation samples.
Subject seeds exposed to radiation.
90%.
Absorption level as expected.
Irregular molecular stimulation noted in subject seeds.
95%.
98%.
The power objective has been attained.
Molecular activity is exceeding the control model.
The thermal levels continuing to accelerate.
Thermal levels exceeding safety parameters.
The temperature is climbing past the target range.
Turn it down.
I'm trying, sir.
I'm trying.
Thermal levels exceeding safety parameters.
Get out of here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, you critical.
Ah!
Oh.
Are you okay?
I'm calling this a little failure.
Come on, Dr. Sinclair.
I'll get you to the hospital.
I made this whole world shine for you.
Yeah, yeah, come on.
Lex, are you okay?
Clark, I'm fine.
How did you know I was here?
One of your EMTs is a friend of mine.
She said there was an explosion at Luther Park.
What happened?
Nothing.
We were conducting an experiment.
I'm guessing it didn't go well.
Not exactly as I hoped, but it was worth the risk.
I'm sure it was.
To Luther Corp's bottom line.
To the world, Chloe.
Look, why don't the two of you come with me to the lab,
and I'll show you what Dr. Sinclair and I have been working on.
I really think you're gonna like this one.
All right, let's go.
Clark, wait.
I'm not buying any story from a Luther without corroboration.
So I'm gonna go talk to Dr. Sinclair
and find out what he has to say about this.
Okay.
I'll check out the lab with Lex.
Just be careful, okay?
I mean, no matter what he says,
Luther Corp experiments never end well.
I'm sorry.
Is thereogene a Red 13 quicker?
Girl's, I'll take out one of these machine guns.
Fine, that thing's tame.
Here you go.
Okay.
This is what I started magnetism.
I didn't do my makeup.
That gotta be better, church.
That's better.
listened?
I think the explosion caused some kind of separation.
A division at the molecular level, I don't know,
but I saw myself, Doctor.
I saw another Lex Luthor.
My God.
What about reversing it?
Is there any way to force the two knees back together?
My research notes are back in the lab,
and if I had those,
I might be able to find a way to reverse the process.
I'm gonna go back to the lab and get the notes.
In the meantime,
why don't you get some rest?
I don't know.
I'm gonna go.
Lex?
Chloe.
I thought you left for the lab with Clark.
I just wanted to check in on Dr. Sinclair first.
Oh, is he all right?
Not feeling a thing.
Well, I was hoping I could maybe talk to him.
Well, he's sleeping now.
Maybe he should come back later when he's feeling a little more alive.
Okay.
Call Blue, room 213. Call Blue, room 213.
Coming through!
He's a rat face.
Set.
200.
Clear.
No response.
250.
Clear.
Still no response.
This is what your secret experiment was about?
Gardening?
No, Clark.
It's about the future.
These are growing in common sand with only a few drops of water.
I'm sure you've seen them.
I've seen them.
Water is irrigation.
If my dad planted a crop of these, he'd never have to worry about the harvest again.
Until it arrived at your dinner table.
Taste it.
It was grown from irradiated seeds.
Well, if something's wrong, it tastes rotten.
That's what we've been wrestling with.
See, we've successfully destroyed the genes that make a plant weak,
giving it the ability to thrive under the harshest conditions.
But the process also affects the fruit of the plant.
It bears, but not for the better.
Is that what you were trying to fix when the explosion happened?
Dr. Sinclair thought increasing the temperature of the reaction would solve the problem.
We pushed it further than we ever have, Clark.
But the meteorite became unstable.
Wait.
You're working with meteorites again?
If I could find a way to make this work, LuthorCorp could put an end to hunger and
famine forever.
I'm hoping there's something in Dr. Sinclair's notes that'll explain exactly what went wrong.
I'm gonna get you back.
You're not the only one.
Right.
I'm the only one.
You're the only one.
And I'm the only one.
Okay, I'll be in your care.
What's the plan?
I'm not the only one.
That's all I ever wanna do.
Luthen Corp could put an end to hunger and famine forever.
I'm hoping there's something in Dr. Sinclair's notes
that'll explain exactly what went wrong.
Clark, you all right?
Yeah. I don't think that apple's sitting very well.
I'll wait for you outside.
I'll be right back.
Max.
I haven't forgotten. I know I'm...
I'm not welcome here, but I heard there was an accident at Luthen Corp,
and I wanted to be sure you were all right.
I'm fine, Dad.
Thanks for the concern.
Well...
I'm grateful you're all in one piece.
Sorry. I'm sorry for the intrusion.
Dad.
Are you still planning on your charity fundraiser Saturday?
Yes.
I must say, it's quite an interesting challenge trying to, uh...
to get the Deep Pockets to show up for a salad bar and ginger chicken.
Would it help if the head of Luthen Corp
promised to make an appearance?
Really? You'd do that?
Under one condition.
Oh.
You hold the event on the top floor of Luthen Corp Plaza in Metropolis.
I'll even reach out to a few of those reluctant Deep Pockets.
That's very generous of you. It...
You must be rubbing off on me.
Huh.
I admit I had my doubts about the motives behind your sudden philanthropy,
but I can see how much joy helping the less fortunate is bringing you.
Dad, I'm...
I'm proud of you.
Thank you, Lex.
I'm truly grateful.
For everything.
Hmmm.
Hmm.
Amazing work, isn't it?
Hello, me.
Meet the real you.
Well, I can't have you running about, can I?
Who are you?
That's a question I've been struggling with for years.
I remember the last time we were in this room.
Dad told us not to play down here,
but I whispered in your ear to do it anyway.
I tore a blue shot.
Locked me in. No one could hear me.
You were so frightened.
A scared, trembling child.
I hated you for that.
My God. You're me.
No, Lex.
I'm much, much more.
The explosion in the lab...
Freed me from your weakness.
At last, I can embrace my true destiny.
There. Come on!
Come on, you regret!
Stop me! Come on!
You disappoint me.
As always.
If I'm such a letdown, why don't you just kill me?
Oh.
Nothing would make me happier.
Unfortunately, I don't know what will happen to me if you die.
Are we somehow still connected?
What?
Just like in that Dumas story.
It was always one of our favorites, wasn't it?
King Louis XIV imprisons his twin brother into Bastille,
forcing him to live out his final day.
Behind an iron mask.
No.
See, most people think Louis did it to hide his brother's true identity,
but we know better.
He did it because he couldn't stand looking at such a pale reflection of his own greatness.
No.
No!
Shh, shh, shh.
It's good to be the king.
I guess it's up to me to show the world the real Lex Luthor.
Ah!
Chloe.
Hey.
It's about time. Pretty slow for the quarterback.
Ex-quarterback. What's so important?
Dr. Sinclair.
Did he say something about the explosion at Luthor Corp.?
He couldn't.
He's dead, Clark.
What? What happened?
Cardiac arrest. In a guy with no history of heart problems.
I'd better go tell Lex.
He already knows, I think.
I bumped into him coming out of Dr. Sinclair's room just before he died.
When was this?
Right after you left for the lab.
Well, Chloe, I was with Lex.
We went to the lab together.
Which would be about the same time I was talking to Lex outside Dr. Sinclair's room.
That's impossible.
Not in Smallville.
You of all people should know that.
You know, because of all the weird stuff you've seen.
Well, there must be a way to figure out the timeline.
Yeah, there is.
Smallville Medical Center has a surveillance system,
which, as far as you know, I've never hacked into because that would be wrong.
It's just gonna take a while.
Call me if you find anything.
I'll be right back.
Lex.
What are you doing here?
I got a message on my cell that you wanted to see me.
So you just let yourself in?
My bad.
Would you like me to go?
No, no, uh, it's okay.
You kinda just surprised me.
I've been doing that to a lot of people.
So what can I do for Miss Lang this afternoon?
I wanted to talk to you about Jason.
Oh. Him.
I, uh, I really appreciate everything that you've already told me about Jason and his mom.
Um, but do you, do you really think that...
What I think, Lana?
Is you deserve better.
You deserve to be with someone who recognizes how extraordinary you are.
Lex, what are you doing?
What I've always wanted to.
Oh.
Well, I do like them feisty.
Get out of my apartment!
If that's how you want to play it.
Oh, by the way, I'm closing the talent.
What?!
You can't do that!
Hmmm, I think I can.
Lex, this is my home. Where am I supposed to go?
That's really up to you, isn't it?
Lana, you could live like a queen.
You could live like a queen by my side or get tossed out with the rest of the garbage
Why don't you think about it?
I know I will
Oh
Thanks, what's going on what the hell are you doing seizing the moment dad?
Just like you taught me same time tomorrow
And what's your problem with me this time old man?
It was your offer to hold a fundraiser at Luther court Plaza
Then you go behind my back and cancel the whole thing
Why would you do that because helping those who refuse to help themselves is a waste of time and money son
Doesn't know what the old Lionel Luther used to say I've changed people change legs
No, they don't they just get soft like you
All right, dad
I'll let you have your
little blue plate charity soiree
I'll even make a generous contribution and what would I have to do in exchange for this contribution? Hmm?
I want you to prove you're still worthy to be my father. Are you insane Lex? No
Just curious. I'm not going to fight
Lex stop it
Is your miraculous transformation into the man in the white suit genuine or is it all just an act?
Lex stop this stop it now
Even though the answer to that question or have you been too afraid to ask
What's inside you dad? Is it really just puppies and hugs now or is there something else twisting in your gut squirming to be free again?
I
Know you were in there somewhere father
You should have stayed in prison you were safer there
Oh
You
Lana
, you okay?
You okay?
Yeah
No
Did you know that Lex is going to close the town?
Who told you that?
He did
Well I saw him last night he didn't mention anything
Clark when I um when I came home he was in my apartment
The way he was acting
It's like he was a totally different person
Maybe he was
Do you think that maybe he's having another psychotic break?
You're going to have to go back, you know
It's more complicated than that
It always is isn't it?
You think you know someone
But there's this side of them that you never see
Until it's too late
Well, you certainly see me at my worst.
And at your best.
Come on, I...
Hello.
Clark, I found surveillance footage of Lex and me
outside of Dr. Sinclair's room talking.
And...
you and Lex leaving the med center.
What about the time stamps?
They're identical.
Looks like our favorite billionaire
has one hell of a split personality.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Lex!
I need to talk to you.
This is important.
I always have time for a friend, Clark.
What's on your mind?
What did we talk about last night?
Well, we talked about a lot of things.
The future.
Changing the world.
Reshaping it to a better place.
And you started to feel sick.
You said it was...
You said it was from the apple.
Yeah, that's right.
Clark, what's this all about?
Well, I had to be sure who I was talking to.
What?
Lex, Dr. Sinclair is dead.
Someone murdered him.
Clark, who would do something like that?
Well, you would.
Well, I mean...
I mean, I'm not going to lie to you.
I'm not going to lie to you.
On April 30...
I said so.
You'll feel it, huh?
I'll shame someone who looks like you.
Please.
You know how you feel.
Why'd you kill me, Ch問I mean that?
Well, I knew it before I killed you.
If I have to pay that mee,
I'll feel it.
That's not what I mean.
Like a smoker.
is some kind of copy?
I think he's a part of you that's split off.
I'm gonna put a security team together.
Get Chloe and meet me at the lab.
How will I know it's you?
Well, we could always try a secret handshake.
But I'd like to think you know me better than anyone
after all these years.
Clark, this whole mess is my fault.
But I'll put an end to all of it tonight.
I want to thank you two for bringing this to my attention.
My security team is working to contain the situation.
Is there anything we can do to help?
Excuse me.
Hello.
I'll be right there.
This could be what I was hoping for.
I'll be right back.
Don't worry.
This will all be over soon.
Keep an eye out for my security people.
Chloe, what are you doing?
Snooping where I don't belong.
I'm thinking of making a career out of it.
Well, Lex said he was going to be right back.
How can you be sure it was really him?
I was careful.
Besides, I think I know my own friend, Chloe.
Clark, how many times has your friend
done something underhanded that you didn't expect?
People have a lot of different sides.
And sometimes they keep those sides hidden, even from the ones
that they love.
Sometimes you have to, even if that's not what you want.
Yeah, but sooner or later, you have to trust someone
with what's in your heart.
Otherwise, you're going to end up going through life alone.
smart.
Son of a-
Clark?
What'd you find?
Situation contained.
Chloe.
Chloe?
We really should get you to the hospital.
Yeah, because that worked out really well for Dr. Sinclair.
Clark, I'm fine, okay?
Although, I still can't
figure out how we survived the sky falling on my head.
Can you?
The last thing I remember is I grabbed you
and you dove underneath the lab table.
Must have protected us from the debris.
Good thing our ex-quarterback moves so fast.
Now we're not fast enough.
Clark,
I can live with a couple of bruises,
considering the alternative.
You're always
there when I need you, Clark.
I just hope someday I can do the same for you.
Right now, I just want to make sure you're safe.
I can stay with Lois
at the military base.
Perfect.
Although, getting between her and the general
while they're trying to reconcile
might be just as dangerous.
Watch out, okay?
Lex can be devious enough.
There's no telling what his evil twin is capable of.
I'll be on my cell.
Bye.
Okay.
But if you see him, call me.
And be careful.
Lex really isn't himself.
He's more dangerous than we thought.
Thanks, Lois.
Is that what you think of me, Clark?
I'm hurt.
I thought we were friends.
Where's Lex?
He's standing right in front of you.
No, you're not him.
The real Lex would never try to kill me or Chloe.
Well, you're probably right.
But he's thought about it.
All the times you've meddled in his plans,
derailed his ambitions,
he's thought about killing all of you,
just never had the guts to go through with it.
What are you?
I was just about to ask you the same question.
I dropped half the lab on you and Miss Sullivan,
and yet, here you stand.
I was lucky.
Don't be modest, Clark.
We both know you're much more than that.
It all makes sense now.
That first day on the bridge when we met,
how you were able to save me when my car went into the river,
all the other miraculous times you appeared
in just the right place at just the right moment.
Almost as if you possessed powers and abilities
beyond those of mortal men.
You've lied to me for years, Clark.
But now I know your secret.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't!
I saw you after the explosion.
You lifted a half a ton of concrete like it was nothing.
I should have figured it out a long time ago.
All the pieces were there.
I was just blinded by friendship.
I was blinded by friendship.
A factor that's been removed from the equation.
Whatever you are,
whatever you're planning I'm going to stop you.
No, you aren't.
You're going to join me.
What?
Think about it Clark.
My intellect? Your powers?
Together we can rule this world.
We'll walk as God's among men.
You're not a God. I'm not even sure you're human.
Are you?
Animus.
Is the real Lex still alive?
Oh, you don't get it, do you?
I am the real Lex!
Is he still alive?
Sort of.
I mean, I couldn't really be sure what would happen to me if I killed him,
so I tucked him away where I can keep an eye on him.
Maybe torture him a little when I'm feeling blue.
Where is he?
What's the matter, Clark?
You look a little sick.
Just like back in the lab when you were with the other me.
When he opened the safe door and exposed you to...
Meteor Rock.
Every man has a weakness, Clark.
No matter how superhuman.
Human he may be, I've embraced my destiny.
Now embrace yours.
We can forge a new future together.
I'll never join you.
Yes, you will.
Or everyone you love will suffer!
Clark!
Mom!
Son!
Dad!
Oh, my God!
You're bleeding!
I'm guessing that doesn't happen very often.
Lex!
What did you do?
I gotta hand it to you guys.
I mean, keeping something like this a secret
must have required an impressive ability to obscure the truth.
Maybe the Kents and the Luthers have something in common after all.
After all?
Yeah!
I know about the Green Meteor Rock and Clark's unique gifts.
What do you want?
The world, Mrs. Kent.
And your son's gonna help me bring it to its knees.
Now talk some sense into him before something unfortunate happens.
Like that.
Dad!
You were right about me all along, Mr. Kent.
I am the villain of the story.
Two Lexes.
How the hell did that happen?
There was an accident at Luther Corp,
and I think that Lex was affected by black kryptonite.
How did Lex get a hold of black kryptonite?
Well, I don't think he knows anything about the black K.
I think he accidentally created it
when he was experimenting with the meteor rocks.
Wait, that's how I can put the two Lexes back together.
How?
The duplicate Lex in the barn.
He said he was keeping the real Lex alive,
somewhere close to keep him safe, and if I can find him...
Clark!
How'd he get here?
Lex.
No.
Clark, don't try to talk. Get out.
No, you're gonna be okay, all right?
Get out.
The hero comes to the rescue.
How predictable is that?
Leave him alone.
I'm starting to hate the sound of my own voice.
I offer you a chance at greatness, and this is what you do with it?
No.
I want you to remember this day, Clark.
I want you to remember that despite all your amazing powers,
there was one man that beat you.
Maybe this was always our destiny.
How sad.
Let's see what happens to me if you die.
You can't kill me.
I drive you.
I give your life meaning.
I'm your soul, you weak, pathetic little man.
I'm the real ex-Luther.
I'm the real me.
Lex?
It's all right, it's over now.
It's not much to look at, is it?
Broken dreams seldom are.
Clark,
I want to say thank you for saving me,
but the words seem too small.
Without you, I would have been lost.
You're a true friend.
It's too bad your other half didn't think so.
I'm sorry for what I...
he put you through.
How much of it do you remember?
Nothing, really.
Once we divided, we were two different people.
You might want to go talk to Lana when you get a chance.
He didn't hurt her, did he?
Well, I'm not sure what happened, but...
she seemed pretty upset.
Don't be too hard on yourself. It really wasn't you.
That's what I've been standing here trying to figure out.
Did the accident create an evil Lex?
Or is that what's really inside of me?
Tamam.
He no longer gasped about a single moment he never knows the outcome.
After he escaped from there,
I've been here for a good,
long amount of time.
He hadn't found out any other common memories about me.
I used Googling to keep him away from me.
You're a leader,
and you framed me
with just all this sort of face.
I never got to know anyone about you,
personally
I,
I'm sorry.
No more company laughter or hanging around.
exactly what my other half did so I could apologize properly.
I just hope it wasn't anything we can't get past.
Well, as long as you're not closing the tail end and kicking me out.
I said that?
Along with expressing certain desires?
Lana, I'm sorry.
It wasn't me.
Are you sure?
Look, whatever my feelings are,
I'd never do anything to jeopardize our friendship.
I know.
I really am sorry.
So am I.
Planning an extra salt, son?
Dad, your cheek.
Well, to wake up...
And I'm grateful for that.
Look, whatever I've done in the last few days...
Please, no need for an apology.
Quite the contrary.
I must say, you finally proved yourself to be the son I've always wanted.
And I thank you for showing me so clearly the error of my ways.
What are you talking about?
I'm closing down the Foundation immediately.
What?
You can't. The charity's your life.
Just a foolish dream. I'm awake now.
A man can't deny his true nature.
Can he, Lex?
No. We're Luthers.
We're Luthers.
A woolen Pictures.
Just as a shed.
True working's the only way out.
But not going there was the greatest universal right.
By the fale' of presenteomin'
most
What?
Luthers came with their son?
I'm sorry.